<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Items</name>
    <description>Tregolani Homebrew Feats</description>
    <author>Homebrew</author>
    <update version="0.1.1">
      <file name="homebrew-feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tregolani/Treg-DnD-homebrew/master/homebrew-feats.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
	<element name="Elemental Blood" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD">
		<description>
			<p>Your exposure to the leylines of the Elemental Planes has changed you, granting you the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You learn the <i>alter self</i> spell and one 1st-level spell of your choice. The 1st-level spell must be from the conjuration or transmutation schools of magic. You can cast each of these spells without expending a spell slot. Once you cast either of these spells in this way, you can’t cast that spell in this way again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. The spells’ spellcasting ability is the ability increased by this feat.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can cast this feat’s spells without a spell slot once. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is {{elemental blood:ability}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Ability Score Increase, Elemental Blood" supports="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_INTELLIGENCE|ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_WISDOM|ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_CHARISMA" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Elemental Blood" supports="1,(Conjuration||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_INTELLIGENCE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Intelligence by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Intelligence" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_WISDOM">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Wisdom by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Wisdom" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_CHARISMA">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Charisma" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Healer (Improved)" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_HEALER_IMPROVED">
		<description>
			<p>You are an able physician, allowing you to mend wounds quickly and get your allies back in the fight. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Skill Proficiency.</b> You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
				<li><b>Battle Medic.</b> As an action, you can spend one use of a healer's kit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + your Intelligence or Wisdom Modifier hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to yours or the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice (whichever is higher.) The creature can't regain hit points from this feat again until it finishes a short or long rest.</li>
				<li><b>First Responder.</b> When you use a healer’s kit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains hit points equal to your Intelligence or Wisdom modifier.</li>
				<li><b>Healing Rerolls.</b> Whenever you roll a die to determine the number of hit points you restore with a spell, potion, or any other ability, you can reroll the die if it rolls a 1, and you must use the new roll.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can spend one use of a healer's kit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + {{healer:bonus}} hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to yours or the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice (whichever is higher.) The creature can't regain hit points from this feat again until it finishes a short or long rest.&#13;
			When you use a healer’s kit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains {{healer:bonus}} hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_MEDICINE" />
			<stat name="healer:bonus" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="healer" />
			<stat name="healer:bonus" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="healer" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
