<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Tregolani Homebrew Subclass Revisions</name>
        <description>These are some personal homebrew subclass revisions. Currently contains: Sea Sorcerer</description>
        <author>Tregolani</author>
        <update version="0.3.4">
            <file name="homebrew-subclass-revision.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tregolani/Treg-DnD-homebrew/master/homebrew-subclass-revision.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
	    <!-- Sea Sorcery -->
      <element name="Sea Sorcerer" type="Archetype" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_SEA_SORCERER">
          <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
          <description>
            <p>The power of water is the strength of flexibility, resilience, and a relentless nature. Water parts to allow a ship to sail over it or a diver to plunge into it, but their passing leaves no mark. Water flowing down a mountain reaches the sea. It might bend and turn across valleys and down hillsides, but it slowly and steadily returns to the waves. Those whose souls are touched by the power of elemental water command a similar power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your heritage ties to powerful creatures of the sea, such as nereids, the lords of the merfolk, and elemental powers. Like a river, you feel the call of the ocean. The call is ever present in your heart, and you are never completely at peace until you are near the sea.</p>
            <div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SOUL_OF_THE_SEA" />
	    <div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_OCEAN_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_CURSE_OF_THE_SEA" />
            <div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATERY_DEFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SHIFTING_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATER_SOUL" />
          </description>
          <sheet>
            <description>Your soul's heritage ties to powerful creatures and deities of the sea.</description>
          </sheet>
          <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SOUL_OF_THE_SEA" level="1" />
	    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_OCEAN_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_CURSE_OF_THE_SEA" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATERY_DEFENSE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SHIFTING_FORM" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATER_SOUL" level="18" />
          </rules>
      </element>

      <element name="Soul of the Sea" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SOUL_OF_THE_SEA">
        <description>
          <p>At 1st level, your tie to the sea grants you the ability to breathe underwater, and you have a swim speed equal to your walking speed. You also can speak, read, and write Primordial, the language of the elemental planes.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>You can breathe underwater, have a swimming speed of {{speed}} feet, and can speak, read, and write Primordial.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
          <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
	  <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_PRIMORDIAL" />
        </rules>
      </element>

      <element name="Ocean Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_OCEAN_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p><em>1st-level Sea Sorcerer feature</em></p>
			<p>You learn additional spells when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown on the Oceanic Spells table. Each of these spells counts as a sorcerer spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of sorcerer spells you know.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you gain a sorcerer level, you can replace one spell you gained from this feature with another spell of the same level. The new spell must be a conjuration or a transmutation spell from the druid, sorcerer, or wizard spell list.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Oceanic Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
                	<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>create or destroy water, fog cloud</em></td></tr>
                	<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gust of wind, misty step</em></td></tr>
                	<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>tidal wave, wind wall</em></td></tr>
                	<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>control water, storm sphere</em></td></tr>
                	<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>maelstrom, control winds</em></td></tr>
	    </table>
			<p>Additionally, your aquatic soul lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a sorcerer spell. The following spells are added to the sorcerer spell list for you.</p>
      <h5 class="caption">Sea Sorcerer Expanded Spell List</h5>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr></thead>
          <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>control weather, tsunami</em></td></tr>
        </table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you gain a sorcerer level, you can replace one spell you gained from this feature with another spell of the same level. The new spell must be a conjuration or a transmutation spell from the druid, sorcerer, warlock, or wizard spell list.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="1,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)||Create or Destroy Water" level="1" default="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="1,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)" level="1" default="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="2,(Transmutation||Conjuration||Gust of Wind),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)" level="3" default="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="2,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)" level="3" default="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="3,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)" level="5" default="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="3,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)||Wind Wall" level="5" default="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="4,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)||Control Water" level="7" default="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="4,(Transmutation||Conjuration||Storm Sphere),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)" level="7" default="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="5,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)||Maelstrom" level="9" default="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Oceanic Spells" supports="5,(Transmutation||Conjuration),(($(spellcasting:list))||Druid||Wizard)" level="9" default="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
<!--
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />-->
		</rules>
		<spellcasting name="Sorcerer" extend="true">
				<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WEATHER</extend>
				<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_TSUNAMI</extend>
		</spellcasting>
      </element>

      <element name="Curse of the Sea" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_CURSE_OF_THE_SEA">
        <description>
          <p>When you choose this origin at 1st level, you learn the secret of infusing your spells with a watery curse.</p>
          <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with a spell’s attack or when a creature fails a saving throw against your spell, you can curse the target for 1 minute. You can maintain a number of curses on creatures equal to your proficiency bonus. If you curse another creature in excess of this number, you must end the curse on a cursed creature.</p>
          <p class="indent">Once per turn when you hit with a spell, you can trigger the curse if that spell deals cold or lightning damage to the cursed target or forces it to move. Doing so subjects the target to the appropriate additional effect below (you choose the effect to use if more than one effect applies):</p>
          <ul>
            <li><b>Cold Damage: </b>If the affected target takes cold damage from your spell, the target’s speed is also reduced by 15 feet until the end of your next turn. If the spell already reduces the target’s speed, use whichever reduction is greater.</li>
            <li><b>Lightning Damage: </b>If the affected target takes lightning damage from your spell, the target takes additional lightning damage equal to your Charisma modifier.</li>
            <li><b>Forced Movement: </b>If the target is moved by your spell, increase the distance it is moved by 15 feet.</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
            When you hit a creature with a spell’s attack or when a creature fails a saving throw against your spell, you can curse the target for 1 minute. You can maintain up to {{proficiency}} curses on creatures at a time. If you curse another creature in excess of this number, you must end the curse on a cursed creature.&#13; 
            Once per turn when you hit with a spell, you can trigger the curse if that spell deals cold or lightning damage to the cursed target or forces it to move. Doing so subjects the target to the appropriate additional effect below (you choose the effect to use if more than one effect applies):&#13;
            •Cold Damage: Target's speed is reduced by 15 feet until the end of your next turn.&#13;
            •Lightning Damage: Target takes an additional {{charisma:modifier}} lightning damage.&#13;
            •Forced Movement: Increase the distance moved by 15 feet
          </description>
        </sheet>
      </element>
      <element name="Watery Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATERY_DEFENSE">
        <description>
          <p>At 6th level, you gain resistance to fire and poison damage, and have advantage on saving throws against poison.</p>
          <p class="indent">You also gain the ability to defend yourself by momentarily assuming a watery form. As a reaction when you are hit by an attack and take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage from the attack, you can reduce that damage by an amount equal to your sorcerer level plus your Charisma score. You can then move up to 30 feet without provoking opportunity attacks, ignoring any ability or condition that reduces your movement speed. Once you use this special reaction, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest, or until you spend 4 sorcery points as a bonus action to replenish it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest" alt="Watery Defense">
          <description>
            You gain resistance to fire damage. As a reaction when you are hit by an attack dealing bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, you can reduce that damage by {{watery defense}} and then move up to 30 feet without provoking opportunity attacks, ignoring any condition or ability that reduces movement speed. Once you use this special reaction, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest, or until you spend 4 sorcery points as a bonus action to replenish it.
          </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
	  <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
	  <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
          <stat name="watery defense" value="level:sorcerer" />
          <stat name="watery defense" value="charisma:score" />
        </rules>
      </element>

      <element name="Shifting Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SHIFTING_FORM">
        <description>
          <p>Starting at 14th level, when you move on your turn, you take only half damage from opportunity attacks, and you can move through any enemy's space. If you move through a creature's space, you can use your bonus action to apply your <em>Curse of the Sea</em> to the target, as if you had successfully affected it with a spell.</p>
          <p class="indent">On your turn, you can move through any space that is at least 3 inches in diameter and do so without squeezing. When you stop moving, the regular squeezing rules apply if you're in a space one size smaller than you. You can't willingly stop in a space smaller than that, and if you're forced to do so, you immediately flow to the nearest space that can fit you, back along the path of your movement.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
		When you move on your turn, you take only half damage from opportunity attacks, and you can move through any enemy's space. If you move through a creature's space, you can use your bonus action to apply your Curse of the Sea to  the target.&#13;
		On your turn, you can move through any space that is at least 3 inches in diameter. When you stop moving, the regular squeezing rules apply if you're in a space one size smaller than you. You can't willingly stop in a space smaller than that, and if you're forced to do so, you immediately flow to the nearest space that can fit you, back along the path of your movement.
          </description>
        </sheet>
      </element>

      <element name="Water Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATER_SOUL">
        <description>
          <p>Starting at 18th level, you gain the following benefits:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>You no longer require air, food, drink, or sleep, and can’t be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as keeping watch.</li>
            <li>A critical hit against you becomes a normal hit.</li>
            <li>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, and immunity to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
		  You gain the following benefits:&#13;
		  •You no longer require air, food, drink, or sleep, and can’t be forced to sleep by any means.&#13;
		  •A critical hit against you becomes a normal hit.&#13;
		  •You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, and immunity to poison damage and the poisoned condition.
          </description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_SLASHING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />	
		</rules>
      </element>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER">
		<supports>Create or Destroy Water</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND">
		<supports>Gust of Wind</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL">
		<supports>Wind Wall</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER">
		<supports>Control Water</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE">
		<supports>Storm Sphere</supports>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM">
		<supports>Maelstrom</supports>
	</append>
</elements>
