<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Items</name>
    <description>Tregolani Homebrew Feats</description>
    <author>Homebrew</author>
    <update version="0.1.4">
      <file name="thc-feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tregolani/Treg-DnD-homebrew/master/thc-feats.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
	<element name="Elemental Blood" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD">
		<description>
			<p>Your exposure to the leylines of the Elemental Planes has changed you, granting you the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You learn the <i>alter self</i> spell and one 1st-level spell of your choice. The 1st-level spell must be from the conjuration or transmutation schools of magic. You can cast each of these spells without expending a spell slot. Once you cast either of these spells in this way, you can’t cast that spell in this way again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. The spells’ spellcasting ability is the ability increased by this feat.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can cast this feat’s spells without a spell slot once. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is {{elemental blood:ability}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Ability Score Increase, Elemental Blood" supports="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_INTELLIGENCE|ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_WISDOM|ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_CHARISMA" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Elemental Blood" supports="1,(Conjuration||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_INTELLIGENCE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Intelligence by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Intelligence" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_WISDOM">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Wisdom by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Wisdom" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_CHARISMA">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Charisma" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Healer (Improved)" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_HEALER_IMPROVED">
		<description>
			<p>You are an able physician, allowing you to mend wounds quickly and get your allies back in the fight. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Skill Proficiency.</b> You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
				<li><b>Battle Medic.</b> As an action, you can spend one use of a healer's kit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + your Intelligence or Wisdom Modifier hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to yours or the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice (whichever is higher.) The creature can't regain hit points from this feat again until it finishes a short or long rest.</li>
				<li><b>First Responder.</b> When you use a healer’s kit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains hit points equal to your Intelligence or Wisdom modifier.</li>
				<li><b>Healing Rerolls.</b> Whenever you roll a die to determine the number of hit points you restore with a spell, potion, or any other ability, you can reroll the die if it rolls a 1, and you must use the new roll.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can spend one use of a healer's kit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + {{healer:bonus}} hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to yours or the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice (whichever is higher.) The creature can't regain hit points from this feat again until it finishes a short or long rest.&#13;
			When you use a healer’s kit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains {{healer:bonus}} hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_MEDICINE" />
			<stat name="healer:bonus" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="healer" />
			<stat name="healer:bonus" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="healer" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Skeptic" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_SKEPTIC">
		<prerequisite>Wisdom 13 or higher</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[wis:13]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You are exacting by nature, and slow to trust the word of others. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you gain expertise instead.</li>
				<li>You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Insight) score and have advantage on Insight checks to determine if creatures are lying.</li>
				<li>When you make an Insight check, you can choose to learn what the creature's bonus to Charisma (Deception) checks is. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus. Once you have, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INSIGHT" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_INSIGHT_BOOST" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_DECEPTION_ASSESSMENT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Insight Boost" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_INSIGHT_BOOST">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Insight) score and have advantage on Insight checks to determine if creatures are lying.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Insight) score and have advantage on Insight checks to determine if creatures are lying.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="insight:passive" value="5" />
		</rules>	
	</element>
	<element name="Deception Assessment" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_DECEPTION_ASSESSMENT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you make an Insight check, you can choose to learn what the creature's bonus to Charisma (Deception) checks is. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus. Once you have, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you make an Insight check, you can choose to learn what the creature's bonus to Charisma (Deception) checks is.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Titan Grip" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_TITAN_GRIP">
			<prerequisite>Strength 15</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[str:15]</requirements>
			<description>
			<p>You've learned to use the weight of your weapons effectively and have adapted to use large weapons one-handed.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Guts Grip.</b> You may wield a two-handed melee weapon in one hand, treating it as a one-handed weapon. If you do, reduce the damage die by one step. For example, a greatsword or greataxe wielded in one hand deals 1d10 damage.</li>
				<li><b>Heavy Handed.</b> The one- and two-handed damage die for versatile melee weapons you wield increases by 1 step. For example, a longsword deals 1d10 damage in one hand or 1d12 damage in two.</li>
				<li><b>Versatility.</b> You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls with light melee weapons. You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with heavy melee weapons. Increase the range you score a critical hit with a melee weapon that is neither heavy or light by 1.</li>
				<li><b>Weightless Weapons.</b> You can ignore the heavy quality on weapons you wield, or add the light quality to weapons without the heavy quality (no action required). You may wield heavy weapons without penalties if you are Small or smaller.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You may wield two-handed melee weapons in one hand, reducing their damage die by one step&#13;
			You may increase the damage die of versatile melee weapons by one step.&#13;
			Gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls with light melee weapons, a +2 bonus to damage rolls with heavy melee weapons, or increase the critical range of melee weapons that are neither heavy or light by 1.&#13;
			Can ignore the heavy quality on melee weapons, or add the light quality to all other melee weapons.&#13;
			Can wield heavy weapons without penalty if you are Small or smaller.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
