<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Items</name>
    <description>Tregolani Homebrew Items</description>
    <author>Homebrew</author>
    <update version="0.2.14">
      <file name="thc-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tregolani/Treg-DnD-homebrew/master/thc-items.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

<!--Wondrous Items-->
	<element name="Cursed Amulet of the Chameleon" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_ALTER_SELF">
		<description>
			<p>A simple silver chain adorned with an intricately carved depiction of a chameleon with a small jade gem inset for its eye. Small runes run surround the gem, depicting the elvish word "aethen".</p>
			<p>While attuned to this amulet, you can touch the gem and speak the command word <em>"aethen"</em> to transform your appearance. You decide what you look like, including your height, weight, facial features, sound of your voice, hair length, coloration, and distinguishing characteristics, if any. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your statistics change. You cannot appear as a creature of a different size than you, and your basic shape stays the same; if you’re bipedal, you can’t use this amulet to become quadrupedal, for instance. The transformation ends when the wearer touches the gem and speaks the command word again.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Cursed:</em></strong> This item is cursed. Attuning to it inflicts a debilitating curse which saps the wearer's physical body, permanently reducing your Strength score by 1 for each year you remain attuned to the amulet. As long as you remain cursed, you cannot discard the amulet (which immediately teleports back into your pocket or pack), nor can you break your attunement with it. This curse cannot be removed until you are targeted by a <em>remove curse</em> spell or similar magic of at least 5th level, but your reduced Strength score cannot be restored by anything other than a <em>wish</em> spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">transmutation</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Handwraps of the Flowing Soul, +1" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_HANDWRAPS_OF_THE_FLOWING_SOUL_1">
		<description>
			<p>These fine silk handwraps are trimmed with a flowing pattern of golden thread. While you wear these handwraps, your unarmed attacks gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls, and you gain a +1 bonus to your Ki saving throw DC.</p>
			<p>Once per turn, whenever you score a critical hit with your unarmed or monk weapon attacks against another creature, you regain 1 expended ki point.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">monk</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a monk">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ki:dc" value="1" bonus="handwraps of the flowing soul" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Handwraps of the Flowing Soul, +2" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_HANDWRAPS_OF_THE_FLOWING_SOUL_2">
		<description>
			<p>These fine silk handwraps are trimmed with a flowing pattern of golden thread. While you wear these handwraps, your unarmed attacks gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls, and you gain a +2 bonus to your Ki saving throw DC.</p>
			<p>Once per turn, whenever you score a critical hit with your unarmed or monk weapon attacks against another creature, you regain 1 expended ki point.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">monk</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a monk">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ki:dc" value="2" bonus="handwraps of the flowing soul" />
		</rules>
	</element>	<element name="Handwraps of the Flowing Soul, +3" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_HANDWRAPS_OF_THE_FLOWING_SOUL_3">
		<description>
			<p>These fine silk handwraps are trimmed with a flowing pattern of golden thread. While you wear these handwraps, your unarmed attacks gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls, and you gain a +3 bonus to your Ki saving throw DC.</p>
			<p>Once per turn, whenever you score a critical hit with your unarmed or monk weapon attacks against another creature, you regain 1 expended ki point.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">monk</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a monk">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ki:dc" value="3" bonus="handwraps of the flowing soul" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sentinel Shield +1" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_SENTINEL_SHIELD_1">
		<description>
			<p>While holding this shield, you gain a +1 to your AC and have advantage on initiative rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks. The shield is emblazoned with a symbol of an eye.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_INITIATIVE_ADVANTAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Quiver of Radiance" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_QUIVER_OF_RADIANCE">
		<description>
			<p>This leather quiver is embossed with intricate Evocation runes. When a common arrow is stored in the quiver for a minimum of one hour, the arrow is imbued with magical energy. Arrows pulled from this quiver shine with dim light in a 5-foot radius. When a successful attack is made with an arrow pulled from this quiver, the attack deals an additional 1d6 radiant damage to the target. Once the arrow is fired, it will not deal radiant damage again until it is stored in the quiver for a minimum of one hour.</p>
			<p class="indent">The quiver can hold a maximum of 20 arrows at a time, and has no effect on arrows that already contain magical properties</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Land of the Dead Focus-Stone" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_LAND_OF_THE_DEAD_FOCUS_STONE">
		<description>
			<p>This is far from an ordinary rock—the extra-planar nature of this stone has imbued it with magical storing properties.</p>
			<p class="indent">This stone stores necromancy spells cast into it, holding them until the attuned holder uses them. The stone can store up to 5 levels worth of spells at a time. When found, it contains 1d6-1 levels of stored spells chosen by the DM.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature can cast a spell of 1st through 5th level into the stone by touching the stone as the spell is cast. The spell has no effect, other than to be stored in the stone. If the stone can't hold the spell, the spell is expended without effect. If a spell other than one from the school of Necromancy is cast on the stone, the spell is expended without effect. The level of the slot used to cast the spell determines how much space it uses.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding this stone, you can cast any spell stored in it. The spell uses the slot level, spell save DC level, spell attack bonus, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell. The spell cast from the stone is no longer stored in it, freeing up space.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Earrings of Alluring Charisma" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_EARRINGS_OF_ALLURING_CHARISMA">
		<description>
			<p>These magical earrings, set with brilliant ever-glinting rubies, convey an aura of gregariousness upon the wearer. While worn, the wearer's Charisma score is increased by 6, to a maximum of 20. If their Charisma score is already 20 without the earrings, they can instead bring the wearer's Charisma score to a maximum of 22.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">charisma</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">ear</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Necklace of Inspired Wisdom" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_NECKLACE_OF_INSPIRED_WISDOM">
		<description>
			<p>This simple chain, adorned with a small silver pendant inset with an opal, carries with it the collective ageless wisdom of those who have touched it before. While worn, the wearer's Wisdom score is increased by 6, to a maximum of 20. If their Wisdom score is already 20 without the necklace, they can instead bring the wearer's Wisdom score to a maximum of 22.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">wisdom</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sandals of Incredible Dexterity" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_SANDALS_OF_INCREDIBLE_DEXTERITY">
		<description>
			<p>These soft shoes, constructed of an impossibly supple leather, bestow an uncanny poise and balance to the wearer's movements. While worn, the wearer's Dexterity score is increased by 6, to a maximum of 20. If their Dexterity score is already 20 without the sandals, they can instead bring the wearer's Dexterity score to a maximum of 22.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dexterity</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">foot</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="6" />
		</rules>
	</element>

<!--Staffs-->
	<element name="Captain's Wright" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag" id="ID_TGS_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_CAPTAINS_WRIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>This walking cane—a gift from Lady Annette Drask following their voyage from Galeran to Dun'Morach—is made of dark ebony and inlaid with narwhal ivory. Coiled around the cane's straight handle is carved the alluring likeness of a mermaid, her swirling hair made of polished pearl. A small clasp can be undone to allow the handle to pull free from the rest of the cane, revealing a short, pointed blade that functions as a standard dagger.</p>
			<p class="indent">While on a vehicle, you can use the staff to perform a ritual over the course of 1 minute. At the end of the ritual, you and the staff are magically linked to that vehicle. While holding the staff, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>While you are within 10 miles of the linked vehicle, you can notice and identify damage taken by it as if you suffered the injury yourself. The sensation is harmless.</li>
				<li>While you are within 1 mile of the linked vehicle, you can use an action to see and hear as if you were in any space on or adjacent to it until the start of your next turn. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses.</li>
				<li>While you are within 100 feet of the linked vehicle, you can use an action to cause the sound of your voice to originate from any point on or adjacent to it. While speaking in this way, you can make your voice boom up to three times as normal until the start of your next turn.</li>
				<li>As an action, or as part of an action made to control the linked vehicle, you can touch it and expend one Hit Die to repair it. Roll the die twice. The vehicle regains a number of hit points equal to the total of the two rolls, plus your Constitution modifier.</li>
				<li>Any creature that can see or hear you, including yourself, has advantage on any check made to control or repair the linked vehicle.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Your link to a vehicle ends when the vehicle is destroyed. It ends early if you use an action to mentally sever the link, or if you perform the ritual again with a different vehicle. If the linked vehicle is destroyed, you also take 3d10 psychic damage before the link is severed.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Spells.</em></strong> The staff has 10 charges. While holding the staff, you can use an action to expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it: <em>animal messenger</em> (1 charge), <em>floating disk</em> (1 charge), <em>levitate</em> (2 charges), <em>mending</em> (no charges), <em>rope trick</em> (2 charges), <em>teleport</em> (7 charges), or <em>water walk</em> (3 charges). This version of the teleport spell targets only yourself, and the destination must be a location on the linked vehicle. The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff loses this property.</p>
		</description>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_MESSENGER" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TENSERS_FLOATING_DISK" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ROPE_TRICK" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT" />
		</rules>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type" addition="quarterstaff">Weapon</set>
			<set name="name-format">Captain's Wright</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="charges">10</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!--Tools-->
	<element name="Surgeon's tools" type="Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ITEM_TOOL_SURGEONS_TOOLS">
		<description>
			<p>This black leather bag contains everything you'd need to perform surgery.  Proficiency with these tools allows you to add your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make to perform surgery or autopsy. Proficiency with surgeons' tool is required to attempt surgery.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Components.</em></strong> Surgeon's tools include anesthetics, scalpels, clamps, bandages, salves, and catgut sutures imbued with healing potion residue to help speed healing and prevent infection.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Investigation and Insight.</em></strong> When examining a creature, your expertise lends additional insight to the history and nature of external wounds, scars or deformities.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Medicine.</em></strong> Your mastery of medicinal tools improves your ability to treat wounds directly and efficiently.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Nature.</em></strong> A creature's abilities are inherent to their physiology. When examining or dissecting a creature, you gain insights into its habits, environment, and possibly any strange or unique abilities it might have.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Tools</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lbs.</set>
			<set name="type">Tool</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SURGEONS_TOOLS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Tool Proficiency (Surgeon's tools)" type="Proficiency" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SURGEONS_TOOLS">
		<supports>Tool, Artisan tools</supports>
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan’s tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft.</p>
		</description>
		<rules />
	</element>
	<element name="Tattooist's tools" type="Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ITEM_TOOL_TATTOOISTS_TOOLS">
		<description>
			<p>This thick leather satchel contains everything you'd need to apply a tattoo to someone's skin. Proficiency with these tools allows you to add your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make to apply or attempt to remove a tattoo.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Components.</em></strong> Tattooist's tools include anesthetics, needles, brushes, salves, and various types and colors of ink.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Medicine.</em></strong> Your mastery of after-application salving improves your ability to treat wounds directly and efficiently.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sleight of Hand.</em></strong> One must have a steady hand when applying a tattoo to a creature's skin. Your proficiency with these tools grants you additional finesse when attempting other sorts of similar tasks, such as picking a lock or sewing with needle and thread.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Tools</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">20</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lbs.</set>
			<set name="type">Tool</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TATTOOISTS_TOOLS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Tool Proficiency (Tattooist's tools)" type="Proficiency" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TATTOOISTS_TOOLS">
		<supports>Tool, Artisan tools</supports>
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>These special tools include the items needed to pursue a craft or trade. Proficiency with a set of artisan’s tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make using the tools in your craft.</p>
		</description>
		<rules />
	</element>
	
	<!-- Extra Class Features -->
	<!-- Catalyst of Magic -->
<!--	<element name="Catalyst of Magic" type="Class Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_CATALYST_OF_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p>At 2nd level, as your control over your innate magic grows, you can now use yourself as an arcane focus for your spells. Additionally, by spending 2 sorcery points as a reaction, you can allow a creature touching you to use your body as an arcane focus for spells they cast until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Reaction">
			<description>You can now use yourself as an arcane focus for your spells. Additionally, by spending 2 sorcery points as a reaction, you can allow a creature touching you to use your body as an arcane focus for spells they cast until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>-->

	<element name="Sorcerer, LV02: Catalyst of Magic" type="Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ITEM_OCF_SORCERER_CATALYST_OF_MAGIC">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_CATALYST_OF_MAGIC" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">second level, 2nd level</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_CATALYST_OF_MAGIC" requirements="[level:sorcerer:2]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
