<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Items</name>
    <description>Tregolani Homebrew Feats</description>
    <author>Homebrew</author>
    <update version="0.2.2">
      <file name="thc-feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tregolani/Treg-DnD-homebrew/master/thc-feats.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
	<element name="Elemental Blood" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD">
		<description>
			<p>Your exposure to the leylines of the Elemental Planes has changed you, granting you the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You learn the <i>alter self</i> spell and one 1st-level spell of your choice. The 1st-level spell must be from the conjuration or transmutation schools of magic. You can cast each of these spells without expending a spell slot. Once you cast either of these spells in this way, you can’t cast that spell in this way again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. The spells’ spellcasting ability is the ability increased by this feat.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can cast this feat’s spells without a spell slot once. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is {{elemental blood:ability}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Ability Score Increase, Elemental Blood" supports="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_INTELLIGENCE|ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_WISDOM|ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_CHARISMA" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell, Elemental Blood" supports="1,(Conjuration||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_INTELLIGENCE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Intelligence by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Intelligence" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_WISDOM">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Wisdom by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Wisdom" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma (Elemental Blood)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD_CHARISMA">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>ELemental Blood</supports>
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_ELEMENTAL_BLOOD</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Increase your Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" alt="Elemental Blood" />
			<stat name="elemental blood:ability" value="Charisma" inline="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Healer (Improved)" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_HEALER_IMPROVED">
		<description>
			<p>You are an able physician, allowing you to mend wounds quickly and get your allies back in the fight. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Skill Proficiency.</b> You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
				<li><b>Battle Medic.</b> As an action, you can spend one use of a healer's kit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + your Intelligence or Wisdom Modifier hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to yours or the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice (whichever is higher.) The creature can't regain hit points from this feat again until it finishes a short or long rest.</li>
				<li><b>First Responder.</b> When you use a healer’s kit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains hit points equal to your Intelligence or Wisdom modifier.</li>
				<li><b>Healing Rerolls.</b> Whenever you roll a die to determine the number of hit points you restore with a spell, potion, or any other ability, you can reroll the die if it rolls a 1, and you must use the new roll.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can spend one use of a healer's kit to tend to a creature and restore 1d6 + {{healer:bonus}} hit points to it, plus additional hit points equal to yours or the creature's maximum number of Hit Dice (whichever is higher.) The creature can't regain hit points from this feat again until it finishes a short or long rest.&#13;
			When you use a healer’s kit to stabilize a dying creature, that creature also regains {{healer:bonus}} hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_MEDICINE" />
			<stat name="healer:bonus" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="healer" />
			<stat name="healer:bonus" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="healer" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Skeptic" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_SKEPTIC">
		<prerequisite>Wisdom 13 or higher</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[wis:13]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You are exacting by nature, and slow to trust the word of others. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you gain expertise instead.</li>
				<li>You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Insight) score and have advantage on Insight checks to determine if creatures are lying.</li>
				<li>When you make an Insight check, you can choose to learn what the creature's bonus to Charisma (Deception) checks is. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus. Once you have, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INSIGHT" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_INSIGHT_BOOST" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_DECEPTION_ASSESSMENT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Insight Boost" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_INSIGHT_BOOST">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Insight) score and have advantage on Insight checks to determine if creatures are lying.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Insight) score and have advantage on Insight checks to determine if creatures are lying.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="insight:passive" value="5" />
		</rules>	
	</element>
	<element name="Deception Assessment" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEATURE_SKEPTIC_DECEPTION_ASSESSMENT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you make an Insight check, you can choose to learn what the creature's bonus to Charisma (Deception) checks is. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus. Once you have, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you make an Insight check, you can choose to learn what the creature's bonus to Charisma (Deception) checks is.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Titan Grip" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_TITAN_GRIP">
			<prerequisite>Strength 15+</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[str:15]</requirements>
			<description>
			<p>You've learned to use the weight of your weapons effectively and have adapted to use large weapons one-handed.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Guts Grip.</b> You may wield a two-handed melee weapon in one hand, treating it as a one-handed weapon. If you do, reduce the damage die by one step. For example, a greatsword or greataxe wielded in one hand deals 1d10 damage.</li>
				<li><b>Heavy Handed.</b> The one- and two-handed damage die for versatile melee weapons you wield increases by 1 step. For example, a longsword deals 1d10 damage in one hand or 1d12 damage in two.</li>
				<li><b>Versatility.</b> You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls with light melee weapons. You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with heavy melee weapons. For melee weapons that are neither heavy or light, increase the range you score a Critical Hit with them by 1.</li>
				<li><b>Weightless Weapons.</b> You can ignore the heavy quality on weapons you wield, or add the light quality to weapons without the heavy quality (no action required). You may wield heavy weapons without penalties if you are Small or smaller.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You may wield two-handed melee weapons in one hand, reducing their damage die by one step&#13;
			You may increase the damage die of versatile melee weapons by one step.&#13;
			Gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls with light melee weapons, a +2 bonus to damage rolls with heavy melee weapons, or increase the critical range of melee weapons that are neither heavy or light by 1.&#13;
			Can ignore the heavy quality on melee weapons, or add the light quality to all other melee weapons.&#13;
			Can wield heavy weapons without penalty if you are Small or smaller.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Weapon Master" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_NATURAL_WEAPON_MASTER">
			<prerequisite>A natural weapon trait, such as a Bite or Claw attack</prerequisite>
			<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite(s): A natural weapon trait, such as a Bite or Claw attack.</i></p>
			<p>Your natural weapons are more powerful than most.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Swift Claws.</b> You can make one Unarmed Strike as a Bonus Action.</li>
				<li><b>Honed Muscles.</b> The weapon damage die of your natural weapon increases by 1 step. For example, if your weapon deals 1d6 damage, it deals 1d8 instead.</li>
				<li><b>Slayer's Eye.</b> When making an Unarmed Strike, increase the range you score a Critical Hit by 1.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can make one Unarmed Strike as a Bonus Action. The damage die and Critical Hit range of your Unarmed Strikes both increase by 1 step.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Dirty Fighter" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DIRTY_FIGHTER">
			<prerequisite>Strength or Dexterity 13+</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[str:13]||[dex:13]</requirements>
			<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite(s): Strength or Dexterity 13 or higher</i></p>
			<p>You've developed the skills necessary to hold your own in close-quarters grappling. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Attack Advantage.</b> You have advantage on attack rolls against a creature you are grappling.</li>
				<li><b>Damage Rerolls.</b> Whenever you roll a damage die for your Unarmed Strike, you can reroll the die if it rolls a 1, and you must use the new roll.</li>
				<li><b>Fast Wrestler.</b> You do not need to spend extra movement when you move a creature grappled by you, provided the creature is your size or smaller.</li>
				<li><b>Fighting Style.</b> You gain the Unarmed Fighting Style. If you already have this fighting style, you may choose another available to the Fighter class.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on attack rolls against creatures you are grappling, and do not need to spend extra movement when you move a creature grappled by you as long as it is your size or smaller. When you roll damage for an Unarmed Strike, you can reroll the die if it rolls a 1, and you must use the new roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Iron Hero" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_IRON_HERO">
			<prerequisite>Level 12+</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[level:12]</requirements>
			<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite(s): Level 12+</i></p>
			<p>You have steeled yourself against grave threats. When all hope is lost, you stand tall against the storm. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Shadow of the Colossus.</b> You gain a +2 bonus to your Armor Class against creatures of CR greater than or equal to your level. You lose this benefit if you are Charmed or Frightened by the creature, or if you are Incapacitated.</li>
				<li><b>Enrage.</b> You have Advantage on attack rolls against a creature that has reduced one of your allies to 0 Hit Points in the last round.</li>
				<li><b>Quick-Time Event.</b> If a creature you can see within 60 feet takes a Legendary Action, you can use your Reaction to try to interrupt the effect. Choose an ability score you have saving throw proficiency with and make an ability check with it (DC equals 10 plus 3 for each action the Legendary Action expended). On a success, the Legendary Action has no effect, but the actions are still spent. Once this ability successfully negates a Legendary Action, you can't use it again until you finish a Short Rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>If a creature you can see within 60 feet takes a Legendary Action, you can use your Reaction to try to interrupt the effect. Make a {{iron hero:ability score}} ability check (DC10+3 for each action the Legendary Action costs). On a success, the Legendary Action has no effect, but the actions are still spent. Once this ability successfully negates a Legendary Action, you can't use it again until you finish a Short Rest. &#13;
			Additionally, you always have +2 AC against creatures of CR{{level}} or greater, as long as you are not Charmed or Frightened by said creature, or Incapacitated. You have Advantage on attack rolls against a creature that has reduced one of your allies to 0 Hit Points since your last turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Quick-Time Event Ability Score (Iron Hero)" supports="Iron Hero Ability Score" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Strength" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_IRON_HERO_STRENGTH">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Iron Hero Ability Score</supports>
		<requirements>ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Quick-Time Event ability score is Strength.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="iron hero:ability score" value="Strength" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dexterity" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_IRON_HERO_DEXTERITY">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Iron Hero Ability Score</supports>
		<requirements>ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY||ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Quick-Time Event ability score is Dexterity.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="iron hero:ability score" value="Dexterity" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Constitution" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_IRON_HERO_CONSTITUTION">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Iron Hero Ability Score</supports>
		<requirements>ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION||ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Quick-Time Event ability score is Constitution.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="iron hero:ability score" value="Constitution" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_IRON_HERO_INTELLIGENCE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Iron Hero Ability Score</supports>
		<requirements>ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE||ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Quick-Time Event ability score is Intelligence.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="iron hero:ability score" value="Intelligence" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_IRON_HERO_WISDOM">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Iron Hero Ability Score</supports>
		<requirements>ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM||ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Quick-Time Event ability score is Wisdom.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="iron hero:ability score" value="Wisdom" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_IRON_HERO_CHARISMA">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Iron Hero Ability Score</supports>
		<requirements>ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA||ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Quick-Time Event ability score is Charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="iron hero:ability score" value="Charisma" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT">
		<requirements>[level:9]</requirements>
		<supports>General</supports>
		<prerequisite>Level 9+</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite(s): Level 9+</em></p>
			<p>You gain the following benefits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Damage Resistance.</i></b> Choose one damage type. You gain Resistance to that damage type.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase.</i></b> Choose one ability in which you lack saving throw proficiency. Increase the chosen ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Saving Throw Proficiency.</i></b> You gain saving throw proficiency with the chosen ability.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Damage Resistance (Resilient)" supports="THC Resilient Resistance" />
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Saving Throw Proficiency (Resilient)" supports="THC Resilient" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Acid" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_ACID">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Acid Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cold" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_COLD">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Cold Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fire" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_FIRE">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Fire Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Force" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_FORCE">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Force Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FORCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Lightning" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Lightning Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Necrotic" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Necrotic Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Poison" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_POISON">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Poison Damage. You have Advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Poisoned condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Psychic" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Psychic Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Radiant" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_RADIANT">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Radiant Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Thunder" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_RESISTANCE_THUNDER">
		<supports>THC Resilient Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain Resistance to Thunder Damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient (Strength)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_STRENGTH">
		<requirements>!ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH||!ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH</requirements>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>THC Resilient</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with Strength saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Strength Saving Throw Proficiency" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH">
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:save:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" alt="Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient (Dexterity)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_DEXTERITY">
		<requirements>!ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY||!ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY</requirements>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>THC Resilient</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with Dexterity saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dexterity Saving Throw Proficiency" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY">
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity:save:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" alt="Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient (Constitution)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_CONSTITUTION">
		<requirements>!ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION||!ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION</requirements>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>THC Resilient</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with Constitution saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Constitution Saving Throw Proficiency" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION">
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution:save:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" alt="Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient (Intelligence)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_INTELLIGENCE">
		<requirements>!ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE||!ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE</requirements>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>THC Resilient</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with Intelligence saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence Saving Throw Proficiency" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE">
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence:save:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" alt="Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient (Wisdom)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_WISDOM">
		<requirements>!ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM||!ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM</requirements>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>THC Resilient</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with Wisdom saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom Saving Throw Proficiency" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM">
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom:save:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" alt="Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient (Charisma)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_RESILIENT_CHARISMAN">
		<requirements>!ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA||!ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA</requirements>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>THC Resilient</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with Charisma saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma Saving Throw Proficiency" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA">
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma:save:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" alt="Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>

<!-- Solandria-Specific items -->
	<!-- Balm of Peace -->
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Balm of Peace" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_CD_BALM_OF_PEACE">
		<description>
			<p><em>2nd-level Peace Domain feature</em></p>
			<p>You can use your Channel Divinity to make your very presence a soothing balm. As a Magic Action, you can move up to your Speed without provoking opportunity attacks. When you move within 5 feet of any other creature during this Action, you can restore a number of hit points to that creature equal to 2d6 + your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1 hit point). This increases to 3d6 at level 5, 4d6 at level 9, 5d6 at level 13, and 6d6 at level 17. A creature can receive this healing only once whenever you take this Action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Balm of Peace" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description>You can move up to your Speed, without provoking an opportunity attacks, and when you move within 5 feet of any other creature during this action, you can restore {{balm of peace:count}}d6+{{wisdom:modifier}} Hit Points to that creature (minimum of 1). A creature can receive this healing only once whenever you take this action.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="balm of peace:count" value="2" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="balm of peace:count" value="3" bonus="base" level="5"/>
			<stat name="balm of peace:count" value="4" bonus="base" level="9"/>
			<stat name="balm of peace:count" value="5" bonus="base" level="13"/>
			<stat name="balm of peace:count" value="6" bonus="base" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cleric, Peace Domain, LV02: Balm of Peace" type="Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ITEM_OCF_CLERIC_PEACE_BALM_OF_PEACE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_CD_BALM_OF_PEACE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">2nd level, channel divinity, balm of peace</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_TCOE_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_CLERIC_PEACE_DOMAIN_BALM_OF_PEACE" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_CD_BALM_OF_PEACE" requirements="[level:cleric:2]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Favored Foe -->
	<element name="Favored Enemy" type="Class Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY">
		<description>
			<p>You always have the <i>Hunter's Mark</i> spell prepared. You can cast it twice without expending a spell slot, and you regain one use of this ability when you finish a Short Rest, and all uses when you finish a Long Rest. Additionally, when you cast <i>Hunter's Mark</i> in this manner, you can choose to spend additional uses of this ability to increase the damage of the spell by 1d6 per use expended beyond the first.</p>
			<p class="indent">The number of times you can cast the spell without a spell slot increases when you reach certain Ranger levels, as shown in the Favored Enemy column of the Ranger Features table.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Favored Enemy" usage="{{favored enemy:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast Hunter's Mark spell without expending a spell slot. You can expend additional uses to increase the damage of your Hunter's Mark by 1d6 per use expended beyond the first. &#13;
			You regain one use of this ability when you finish a Short Rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK" spellcasting="Ranger" /> 
			<stat name="favored enemy:usage" value="2" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="favored enemy:usage" value="3" bonus="base" level="5"/>
			<stat name="favored enemy:usage" value="4" bonus="base" level="9"/>
			<stat name="favored enemy:usage" value="5" bonus="base" level="13"/>
			<stat name="favored enemy:usage" value="6" bonus="base" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ranger, LV01: Favored Enemy" type="Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ITEM_OCF_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">first level, 1st level, mark, Favored Enemy</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY" requirements="[level:ranger:1]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Tireless -->
	<element name="Level 10: Tireless" type="Class Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_TIRELESS">
		<description>
			<p>Primal forces now help fuel you on your journeys, granting you the following benefits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Temporary Hit Points.</i></b> As a Magic action, you can give yourself a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to 2d8 plus your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1). You can use this action a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Decrease Exhaustion.</i></b> Whenever you finish a Short Rest, your Exhaustion level, if any, decreases by 1.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Tireless" action="Action" usage="{{tireless:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You can give yourself a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to 2d8+{{tireless:thp}}. &#13;
			In addition, whenever you finish a Short Rest, your Exhaustion level decreases by 1.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="tireless:thp" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="tireless:thp" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="tireless:usage" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="tireless:usage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ranger, LV10: Tireless" type="Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ITEM_OCF_RANGER_TIRELESS">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_TIRELESS" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">tenth level, thp, tireless</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_TIRELESS" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_TIRELESS" requirements="[level:ranger:10]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Nature's Veil -->
	<element name="Nature's Veil" type="Class Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_NATURES_VEIL">
		<description>
			<p>You invoke spirits of nature to magically hide yourself. As a Bonus Action, you can give yourself the Invisible condition until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Nature's Veil" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{natures veil:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You can give yourself the Invisible condition until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="natures veil:usage" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="natures veil:usage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ranger, LV10: Nature's Veil" type="Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_ITEM_OCF_RANGER_NATURES_VEIL">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>You can equip this item to “enable” it. It remains hidden from the inventory on your character sheet.</i></p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_NATURES_VEIL" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Optional Class Features</set>
			<set name="keywords">tenth level, 10th level, invisibility</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="inventory-hidden">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_RANGER_NATURES_VEIL" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_NATURES_VEIL" requirements="[level:ranger:10]"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

<!-- Supernatural Gift Feat Chains -->
	<!-- Dragon-Blooded -->
	<element name="Supernatural Gift: Dragon-Blooded" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED">
		<description>
			<p>You are the child of a dragon and a mortal, or were transfigured into a half-dragon through rituals, boons, or exposure to the majesty of the mighty dragons. You gain the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><em><strong>Draconic Ancestry.</strong></em> You have draconic ancestry. Choose one type of damage from the Draconic Ancestry table. Your breath weapon and shape as well as your damage resistance are determined by dragons of that type, as shown in the table. Your ancestry does not necessarily determine your appearance.</li>
			</ul>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Damage Type</td><td>Save Type</td><td>Breath Weapon</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Acid</td><td>Dex</td><td>5 ft. by 30 ft. line</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Cold</td><td>Con</td><td>15 ft. cone</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Fire</td><td>Dex</td><td>15 ft. cone</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Force</td><td>Str</td><td>15 ft. cone</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Lightning</td><td>Dex</td><td>5 ft. by 30 ft. line</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Necrotic</td><td>Con</td><td>15 ft. cone</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Poison</td><td>Con</td><td>15 ft. cone</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Psychic</td><td>Wis</td><td>15 ft. cone</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Radiant</td><td>Dex</td><td>5 ft. by 30 ft. line</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Thunder</td><td>Con</td><td>15 ft. cone</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul>
				<li><em><strong>Breath Weapon.</strong></em> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with an exhalation of magical energy in a shape determined by your Draconic Ancestry. Each creature in that area must make a saving throw (DC = 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus) of a type determined by your Draconic Ancestry. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d10 damage of the type associated with your Draconic Ancestry. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage. This damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</li>
				<li><em><strong>Darkvision.</strong></em> You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 30 feet.</li>
				<li><em><strong>Draconic Resistance.</strong></em> You have resistance to the damage type associated with your Draconic Ancestry. If you choose poison, you have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the @condition[Poisoned] condition on yourself.</li>
				<li><em><strong>Dragonheart.</strong></em> Your creature type is dragon, rather than humanoid.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">If you already have a Breath Weapon or Draconic Resistance trait (such as from the Dragonborn ancestry), work with your DM to find proper replacements. Common alternatives are options from the Draconic Legacy trait, the Half Dragon feat, or the Wyrm-Blessed Supernatural Gift.</p>
			</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your creature type is Dragon. You gain a breath weapon with which you can replace one of your attacks, Resistance to its damage type, and boosted Darkvision.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_DRAGON" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Draconic Ancestry" supports="THC Draconic Ancestry" />
			<stat name="breath weapon:damage" value="1" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="breath weapon:damage" value="2" bonus="base" level="5"/>
			<stat name="breath weapon:damage" value="3" bonus="base" level="11"/>
			<stat name="breath weapon:damage" value="4" bonus="base" level="17"/>
			<stat name="breath weapon:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="breath weapon:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="breath weapon:dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
		</rules>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="type">Supernatural Gift</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Acid" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_ACID">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Acid. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a 5 by {{draconic-ancestry:breath line}}ft. line (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Dex. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_ACID" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath line" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath line" value="60" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cold" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_COLD">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Cold. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a {{draconic-ancestry:breath cone}}ft. cone (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Con. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_COLD" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="15" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="30" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fire" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_FIRE">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Fire. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a {{draconic-ancestry:breath cone}}ft. cone (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Dex. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_FIRE" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="15" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="30" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Force" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_FORCE">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Force. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a {{draconic-ancestry:breath cone}}ft. cone (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Str. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FORCE" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_FORCE" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="15" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="30" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Lightning" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_LIGHTNING">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Lightning. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a 5 by {{draconic-ancestry:breath line}}ft. line (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Dex. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_LIGHTNING" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath line" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath line" value="60" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Necrotic" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_NECROTIC">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Necrotic. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a {{draconic-ancestry:breath cone}}ft. cone (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Con. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_NECROTIC" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="15" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="30" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Poison" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_POISON">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Poison. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a {{draconic-ancestry:breath cone}}ft. cone (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Con. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="15" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="30" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Psychic" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_PSYCHIC">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Psychic. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a {{draconic-ancestry:breath cone}}ft. cone (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Wis. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_PSYCHIC" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="15" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="30" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Radiant" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_RADIANT">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Radiant. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a 5 by {{draconic-ancestry:breath line}}ft. line (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Dex. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_RADIANT" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath line" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath line" value="60" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Thunder" type="Racial Trait" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY_THUNDER">
		<supports>THC Draconic Ancestry</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_DRAGON_BLOODED" />
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Draconic Ancestry" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>Your ancestry is Thunder. Your breath weapon deals {{breath weapon:damage}}d10 damage in a {{draconic-ancestry:breath cone}}ft. cone (DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Con. save).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" requirements="!ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_THUNDER" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING" />
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="15" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="draconic-ancestry:breath cone" value="30" bonus="base" requirements="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Dragon-Blooded: Half-Dragon" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON">
		<requirements>[level:3],ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_DRAGON</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Level 3+, Dragon creature type</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Level 3+, Dragon creature type</em></p>
			<p>The draconic influence which acts upon your essence grows stronger. Choose <b><u>TWO</u></b> of the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b><i>Deep Breath.</i></b> As an Action, you can take a deep breath and unleash your Breath Weapon in a more powerful manner. When you do, the damage increases to a number of d10s equal to half your Proficiency Bonus.</li>
				<li><b><i>Dragon Wrath.</i></b> Once per turn when you damage a creature with a weapon attack or spell, you can also deal 1d8 damage of a type associated with your Draconic Ancestry to that creature.</li>
				<li><b><i>Wings.</i></b> You have bat-like wings sprouting from your shoulder blades. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed.</li>
				<li><b><i>Visage.</i></b> As a Bonus Action, you change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height between Medium and Small. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of an individual you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait. You stay in the new form until you use a Bonus Action to revert to your true form or until you die.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Instead of one of these traits, you may choose <u>two</u> of the following traits instead:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b><i>Amphibious.</i></b> You can breathe air and water, and you have a Swim Speed equal to your Speed.</li>
				<li><b><i>Claws.</i></b> Your claws are natural weapons with the Finesse property, which you can use to make unarmed strikes that deal Slashing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier.</li>
				<li><b><i>Desert Predator.</i></b> You gain a Burrow Speed equal to half your Speed. You have Advantage on Saving Throws against effects from wind or sand.</li>
				<li><b><i>Draconic Hide.</i></b> When you aren't wearing armor, your base AC is 13 + Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.</li>
				<li><b><i>Draconic Senses.</i></b> You gain proficiency in the Perception skill. If you are already proficient in this skill, you gain Expertise instead.</li>
				<li><b><i>Ice Walk.</i></b> You gain a Burrow Speed equal to half your Speed. You can move around on icy surfaces without making ability checks. Difficult terrain composed of ice or snow doesn't cost you extra movement.</li>
				<li><b><i>Rock Climber.</i></b> You have a Climb Speed equal to your Speed.</li>
			</ul>
			</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The draconic influence which acts upon your essence grows stronger.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Half-Dragon" supports="THC Half-Dragon Options" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Deep Breath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_DEEP_BREATH">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>As an Action, you can take a deep breath and unleash your Breath Weapon in a more powerful manner. When you do, the damage increases to a number of d10s equal to your Proficiency Bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You unleash your Breath Weapon in a more powerful manner, dealing {{proficiency}}d10 damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Dragon Wrath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_DRAGON_WRATH">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Once per turn when you damage a creature with a weapon attack or spell, you can also deal 1d8 damage of a type associated with your Draconic Ancestry to that creature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/turn">
			<description>Deal {{dragon wrath:count}}d8 damage to one creature you hit with a weapon attack or spell. The damage type is that of your Draconic Ancestry.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dragon wrath:count" value="1" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wings" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_WINGS">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You have bat-like wings sprouting from your shoulder blades. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a {{speed}}ft. Fly Speed.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="speed" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Visage" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_VISAGE">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>As a Bonus Action, you change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height between Medium and Small. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of an individual you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait. You stay in the new form until you use a Bonus Action to revert to your true form or until you die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height between Medium and Small. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of an individual you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait. You stay in the new form until you use a Bonus Action to revert to your true form or until you die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Physical Traits" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_PHYSICAL_TRAITS">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Instead of one of the base Half-Dragon traits, you can select two of the following traits instead:.</p>
				<ul>
					<li><b><i>Amphibious.</i></b> You can breathe air and water, and you have a Swim Speed equal to your Speed.</li>
					<li><b><i>Claws.</i></b> Your claws are natural weapons with the Finesse property, which you can use to make unarmed strikes that deal Slashing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier.</li>
					<li><b><i>Desert Predator.</i></b> You gain a Burrow Speed equal to half your Speed. You have Advantage on Saving Throws against effects from wind or sand.</li>
					<li><b><i>Draconic Hide.</i></b> When you aren't wearing armor, your base AC is 13 + Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.</li>
					<li><b><i>Draconic Senses.</i></b> You gain proficiency in the Perception skill. If you are already proficient in this skill, you gain Expertise instead.</li>
					<li><b><i>Ice Walk.</i></b> You gain a Burrow Speed equal to half your Speed. You can move around on icy surfaces without making ability checks. Difficult terrain composed of ice or snow doesn't cost you extra movement.</li>
					<li><b><i>Rock Climber.</i></b> You have a Climb Speed equal to your Speed.</li>
				</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your body gains draconic traits.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Half-Dragon Physical Traits" supports="THC Half-Dragon Physical Options" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Amphibious" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_AMPHIBIOUS">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Physical Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You can breathe air and water, and you have a Swim Speed equal to your Speed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can breathe air and water, and you have a {{speed}ft. Swim Speed.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Claws" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_CLAWS">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Physical Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Your claws are natural weapons with the Finesse property, which you can use to make unarmed strikes that deal Slashing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your claws are natural weapons that deal 1d6+{{half-dragon:claws:modifier}} Slashing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="half-dragon:claws:modifier" value="strength:modifier" bonus="ability" />
			<stat name="half-dragon:claws:modifier" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Desert Predator" type="Feat Feature " source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_DESERT_PREDATOR">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Physical Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You gain a Burrow Speed equal to half your Speed. You have Advantage on Saving Throws against effects from wind or sand.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain a {{speed:half}}ft. Burrow Speed. You have Advantage on Saving Throws against effects from wind or sand.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:burrow" value="speed:half" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Draconic Hide" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_DRACONIC_HIDE">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Physical Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>When you aren't wearing armor, your base AC is 13 + Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a base AC of {{ac:draconic hide}} while not wearing armor. You can still benefit from a shield.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:draconic hide" value="13" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="ac:draconic hide" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:draconic hide" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Draconic Hide" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Draconic Senses" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_DRACONIC_SENSES">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Physical Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You gain proficiency in the Perception skill. If you are already proficient in this skill, you gain Expertise instead.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain Proficiency (or Expertise) in Perception.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERCEPTION" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERCEPTION" requirements="ID_WOTC_PHB24_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ice Walk" type="Feat Feature " source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_ICE_WALK">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Physical Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You gain a Burrow Speed equal to half your Speed. You can move around on icy surfaces without making ability checks. Difficult terrain composed of ice or snow doesn't cost you extra movement.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain a {{speed:half}}ft. Burrow Speed. You can move around on icy surfaces without making ability checks. Difficult terrain composed of ice or snow doesn't cost you extra movement.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:burrow" value="speed:half" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Rock Climber" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_ROCK_CLIMBER">
		<supports>THC Half-Dragon Physical Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You have a Climb Speed equal to your Speed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a {{speed}}ft. Climb Speed.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Dragon-Blooded: Soul of the First World" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD">
		<requirements>[level:9],ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Level 9+, Half-Dragon feat</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Level 9+, Half-Dragon feat</em></p>
			<p>Your soul is connected to echoes of draconic might across time and space. You may choose a total of <b><u>TWO</u></b> traits selected from the Half Dragon feat, or from the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b><i>Draconic Size.</i></b> You are Large size, and your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 damage of the same type. <i>[Requires a natural weapon, such as a Bite or Claw attack]</i></li>
				<li><b><i>Empowered Breath Weapon.</i></b> If your breath weapon is a cone, it becomes 30 feet. If your breath weapon is a line, it extends to 60 feet. When you use your breath weapon with the Deep Breath trait, double its range. Additionally, you gain a second breath weapon. When you use your Breath Weapon trait, you can replace your breath weapon with an exhalation of energy in a 30-foot cone (60 feet if you use Deep Breath). Whenever you use this trait, choose:</li>
				<ul>
					<li><b><i>Enervating Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the area must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw or become Incapacitated until the start of your next turn.</li>
					<li><b><i>Nightmare Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the area must succeed on a Wisdom Saving Throw or become Frightened until the start of your next turn.</li>
					<li><b><i>Repulsion Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the area must succeed on a Strength Saving Throw or be pushed 20 feet away from you and be knocked Prone.</li>
					<li><b><i>Sleep Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the area must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw or fall Unconscious for 10 minutes. This effect ends for a creature if the creature takes damage or someone uses an Action to wake it.</li>
					<li><b><i>Slowing Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the area must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw. On a failed save, the creature's Speed is halved, attack rolls against it have Advantage, it has Disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it cannot take Reactions until the end of your next turn.</li>
				</ul>
				<li><b><i>Frightening Presence.</i></b> Creatures of your choice that start their turns within 20 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or be Frightened of you until the start of its next turn. If the creature’s saving throw is successful, it is Immune to this ability for the next 24 hours.</li>
				<li><b><i>Gemstone Telepathy.</i></b> You can communicate telepathically to creatures within 60 feet of you. The contacted creature doesn't need to share a language with you to communicate in this way with it, but it must be able to understand at least one language.</li>
				<li><b><i>Hybrid Draconic Ancestry.</i></b> Choose two additional Draconic Ancestries. You have Resistance to the damage types associated with these Draconic Ancestries. Additionally, when you use your Breath Weapon, you may choose to use the Breath Weapons associated with those Draconic Ancestries.</li>
				<li><b><i>Strong Wings.</i></b> Your Fly Speed increases by 20 feet. <i>[Requires the Wings trait, or an innate flying speed]</i></li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your soul is connected to echoes of draconic might across time and space.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Soul of the First World" supports="THC Half-Dragon Options||THC Soul of the First World Options" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Draconic Size" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_DRACONIC_SIZE">
		<supports>THC Soul of the First World Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You are Large size, and your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 damage of the same type. <i>[Requires a natural weapon, such as a Bite or Claw attack]</i></p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are Large size, and your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 damage</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_LARGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Empowered Breath Weapon" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON">
		<supports>THC Soul of the First World Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>If your breath weapon is a cone, it becomes 30 feet. If your breath weapon is a line, it extends to 60 feet. When you use your breath weapon with the Deep Breath trait, double its range. Additionally, you gain a second breath weapon. When you use your Breath Weapon trait, you can replace your breath weapon with an exhalation of energy in a 30-foot cone (60 feet if you use Deep Breath). Whenever you use this trait, choose:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><b><i>Enervating Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the cone must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw or become Incapacitated until the start of your next turn.</li>
					<li><b><i>Nightmare Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the cone must succeed on a Wisdom Saving Throw or become Frightened until the start of your next turn.</li>
					<li><b><i>Repulsion Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the cone must succeed on a Strength Saving Throw or be pushed 20 feet away from you and be knocked Prone.</li>
					<li><b><i>Sleep Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the cone must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw or fall Unconscious for 10 minutes. This effect ends for a creature if the creature takes damage or someone uses an Action to wake it.</li>
					<li><b><i>Slowing Breath.</i></b> Each creature in the area must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw. On a failed save, the creature's Speed is halved, attack rolls against it have Advantage, it has Disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it cannot take Reactions until the end of your next turn.</li>
				</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The area of your breath weapon increases in size, and you gain a second type of breath weapon that can debilitate creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Empowered Breath Weapon" supports="THC Empowered Breath Weapon Options"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enervating Breath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON_ENERVATING_BREATH">
		<supports>THC Empowered Breath Weapon Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw or become Incapacitated until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Constitution Saving Throw or become Incapacitated until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Nightmare Breath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON_NIGHTMARE_BREATH">
		<supports>THC Empowered Breath Weapon Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Wisdom Saving Throw or become Frightened until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Wisdom Saving Throw or become Frightened until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Repulsion Breath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON_REPULSION_BREATH">
		<supports>THC Empowered Breath Weapon Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Strength Saving Throw or be pushed 20 feet away from you and be knocked Prone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Strength Saving Throw or be pushed 20 feet away from you and be knocked Prone.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sleep Breath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON_SLEEP_BREATH">
		<supports>THC Empowered Breath Weapon Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw or fall Unconscious for 10 minutes. This effect ends for a creature if the creature takes damage or someone uses an Action to wake it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Constitution Saving Throw or fall Unconscious for 10 minutes. This effect ends for a creature if the creature takes damage or someone uses an Action to wake it.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Slowing Breath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON_SLOWING_BREATH">
		<supports>THC Empowered Breath Weapon Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Constitution Saving Throw. On a failed save, the creature's Speed is halved, attack rolls against it have Advantage, it has Disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it cannot take Reactions until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a DC{{breath weapon:dc}} Constitution Saving Throw. On a failed save, the creature's Speed is halved, attack rolls against it have Advantage, it has Disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it cannot take Reactions until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Frightening Presence" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_FRIGHTENING_PRESENCE">
		<supports>THC Soul of the First World Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Creatures of your choice that start their turns within 20 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or be Frightened of you until the start of its next turn. If the creature’s saving throw is successful, it is Immune to this ability for the next 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Creatures of your choice that start their turns within 20 feet of you must make a DC{{frightning presence:DC}} Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened of you until the start of its next turn. If the creature’s saving throw is successful, it is Immune to this ability for the next 24 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="frightning presence:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="frightning presence:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="frightning presence:dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Gemstone Telepathy" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_GEMSTONE_TELEPATHY">
		<supports>THC Soul of the First World Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You can communicate telepathically to creatures within 60 feet of you. The contacted creature doesn't need to share a language with you to communicate in this way with it, but it must be able to understand at least one language.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can communicate telepathically to creatures within 60 feet of you. The contacted creature doesn't need to share a language with you to communicate in this way with it, but it must be able to understand at least one language.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Hybrid Draconic Ancestry" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_HYBRID_DRACONIC_ANCESTRY">
		<supports>THC Soul of the First World Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Choose two additional Draconic Ancestries. You have Resistance to the damage types associated with these Draconic Ancestries. Additionally, when you use your Breath Weapon, you may choose to use the Breath Weapons associated with those Draconic Ancestries.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have two additional Draconic Ancestries</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Draconic Ancestry" supports="THC Draconic Ancestry" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Strong Wings" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_STRONG_WINGS">
		<requirements>[speed:fly:1]</requirements>
		<supports>THC Soul of the First World Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Your Fly Speed increases by 20 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your Fly Speed increases by 20 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Dragon-Blooded: Blood of Asgorath" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH">
		<requirements>[level:12],ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Level 12+, Soul of the First World feat</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Level 12+, Soul of the First World feat</em></p>
			<p>You are as close to a true dragon you can be without a total transformation. You may select a total of two traits selected from the Half-Dragon or Soul of the First World feats, or from the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b><i>Blindsight.</i></b> You gain Blindsight out to 60 feet, and the range of your Darkvision increases by 30 feet. <i>[Requires Expertise in Perception]</i></li>
				<li><b><i>Draconic Warding.</i></b> You become Immune to the damage type associated with all Draconic Ancestries you have.</li>
				<li><b><i>Dragon Outrage.</i></b> The damage of your Dragon Wrath becomes 2d8.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mighty Breath.</i></b> When you use your Breath Weapon using the Deep Breath trait, you can unleash devastation upon your foes by expending two uses of your breath weapon. If you do, choose one of the following modifications of the breath weapon:</li>
				<ul>
					<li><b><i>Obliterate.</i></b> Double the damage dice of your breath weapon.</li>
					<li><b><i>Twin Breath Weapon.</i></b> Creatures who fail the saving throw against your breath weapon are affected by the effects of one of your secondary breath weapons.</li>
					<li><b><i>Shielding Breath Weapon.</i></b> You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to half of the damage roll of your breath weapon.</li>
				</ul>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">When you finish a Short Rest, you regain two uses of your Breath Weapon. <i>[Requires Deep Breath and Empowered Breath Weapon]</i></p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are as close to a true dragon you can be without a total transformation.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Blood of Asgorath" supports="THC Half-Dragon Options||THC Soul of the First World Options||THC Blood of Asgorath Options" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Blindsight" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_BLINDSIGHT">
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB24_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERCEPTION||ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERCEPTION</requirements>
		<prerequisites>Expertise in Perception</prerequisites>
		<supports>THC Blood of Asgorath Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Expertise in Perception</em></p>
			<p>You gain Blindsight out to 60 feet, and the range of your Darkvision increases by 30 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain Blindsight out to 60 feet, and the range of your Darkvision increases by 30 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="30" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Draconic Warding" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRACONIC_WARDING">
		<supports>THC Blood of Asgorath Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You become Immune to the damage type(s) associated with all Draconic Ancestries you have.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You become Immune to the damage type(s) associated with all Draconic Ancestries you have.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Dragon Outrage" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_DRAGON_OUTRAGE">
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_DRAGON_WRATH</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Dragon Wrath</prerequisite>
		<supports>THC Blood of Asgorath Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The damage of your Dragon Wrath becomes 2d8.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your Dragon Wrath is more deadly.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dragon wrath:count" value="1" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mighty Breath" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_BLOOD_OF_ASGORATH_MIGHTY_BREATH">
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_HALF_DRAGON_DEEP_BREATH,ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_DRAGON_BLOODED_SOUL_OF_THE_FIRST_WORLD_EMPOWERED_BREATH_WEAPON</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Deep Breath and Empowered Breath Weapon</prerequisite>
		<supports>THC Blood of Asgorath Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you use your Breath Weapon using the Deep Breath trait, you can unleash devastation upon your foes by expending two uses of your breath weapon. If you do, choose one of the following modifications of the breath weapon:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><b><i>Obliterate.</i></b> Double the damage dice of your breath weapon.</li>
					<li><b><i>Twin Breath Weapon.</i></b> Creatures who fail the saving throw against your breath weapon are affected by the effects of one of your secondary breath weapons.</li>
					<li><b><i>Shielding Breath Weapon.</i></b> You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to half of the damage roll of your breath weapon.</li>
				</ul>
			<p class="indent">When you finish a Short Rest, you regain two uses of your Breath Weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use your Deep Breath Weapon, you can expend 2 uses and modify it in one of the following ways: &#13;
				• Double the damage dice &#13;
				• Apply your Empowered Breath Weapon to creatures who fail the saving throw &#13;
				• Gain THP equal to half the damage roll of your breath weapon &#13;
				You regain 2 uses of your Breath Weapon when you finish a Short Rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- Fey Blessing -->
	<element name="Supernatural Gift: Fey Blessing" type="Magic Item" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_FEY_BLESSING">
		<description>
			<p>Your connection to Faerie is deeper than most. No matter what plane you reside on, the wild energy of the Feywild surges through you. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><em><strong>Fey Ancestry.</strong></em> You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Charmed condition on yourself.</li>
				<li><em><strong>Fey Resistance.</strong></em> Choose <i><u>one</u></i> of the following damage types: Fire, Cold, Lightning, Poison, Psychic, or Thunder. You have Resistance to the chosen damage type. If you choose Poison, you have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Poisoned condition on yourself.</li>
				<li><em><strong>Darkvision.</strong></em> You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 30 feet.</li>
				<li><em><strong>Wild Soul.</strong></em> Your creature type is Fey, rather than Humanoid.</li>
			</ul>
			</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your creature type is Fey. You have Advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Charmed condition, Resistance to {{fey resistance:type}} damage, and boosted Darkvision.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_FEY" />
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Fey Resistance" supports="THC Fey Resistance" />
		</rules>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="type">Supernatural Gift</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cold" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_RESISTANCE_COLD">
		<supports>THC Fey Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have Resistance to Cold damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
			<stat inline="true" name="fey resistance:type" value="Cold" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fire" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_RESISTANCE_FIRE">
		<supports>THC Fey Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have Resistance to Fire damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
			<stat inline="true" name="fey resistance:type" value="Fire" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Lightning" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING">
		<supports>THC Fey Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have Resistance to Lightning damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
			<stat inline="true" name="fey resistance:type" value="Lightning" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Poison" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_RESISTANCE_POISON">
		<supports>THC Fey Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have Resistance to Poison damage, and have Advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the Poisoned condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
			<stat inline="true" name="fey resistance:type" value="Poison" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Psychic" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC">
		<supports>THC Fey Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have Resistance to Psychic damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
			<stat inline="true" name="fey resistance:type" value="Psychic" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Thunder" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_SUPERNATURAL_GIFT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_RESISTANCE_THUNDER">
		<supports>THC Fey Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have Resistance to Thunder damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" />
			<stat inline="true" name="fey resistance:type" value="Thunder" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fey Blessing: Half-Fey" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY">
		<requirements>[level:3],ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_FEY</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Level 3+, Fey creature type</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Level 3+, Fey creature type</em></p>
			<p>Your connections to the Feywild are so deep that you could easily pass as one of the Fair Folk, even to denizens of Faerie.  Choose <b><u>TWO</u></b> of the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Dryad.</i></b> You can communicate with beasts and plants as if you share a language. The starting attitude of beasts and plants is one step higher.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Faun.</i></b> Whenever you make a long or high jump, you can roll a d8 and add the number to the number of feet you cover, even when making a standing jump. This extra distance costs movement as normal. Additionally, you have horns that you can use to make unarmed strikes. When you hit with them, you deal 1d6 + your Strength modifier Piercing damage.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of Glamour.</i></b> You know the <i>Disguise Self</i> spell, and can cast it without expending a spell slot. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell when you cast it (choose when you select this ability).</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Naiad.</i></b> If immersed in water, you can make yourself Invisible as a Bonus Action. You remain Invisible until you leave the water, end it with a Bonus Action, or die.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Pixie.</i></b> You have butterfly-like wings sprouting from your shoulder blades. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of Seasons.</i></b> You become attuned to the primal magic of the seasons. Choose a season to associate yourself with: autumn, winter, spring, or summer. When finishing a Long Rest, you can change your season. As a bonus action, you can Fey Step, magically teleporting up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see and triggering an additional effect based on your current choice of season. If the effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma modifier (choose when you select this trait). You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</li>
					<ul>
						<li><b><i>Autumn.</i></b> Immediately after you use your Fey Step, up to two creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</li>
						<li><b><i>Winter.</i></b> When you use your Fey Step, one creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you before you teleport must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</li>
						<li><b><i>Spring.</i></b> When you use your Fey Step, you can touch one willing creature within 5 feet of you. That creature then teleports instead of you, appearing in an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you.</li>
						<li><b><i>Summer.</i></b> Immediately after you use your Fey Step, each creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you takes fire damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</li>
					</ul>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Treetops.</i></b> Your Speed increases by 10 feet, and you have a Climb Speed equal to your Speed.</li>
			</ul>
			</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your connections to the Feywild are so deep that you could easily pass as one of the Fair Folk.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Half-Fey" supports="THC Half-Fey Options" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Dryad" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_THE_DRYAD">
		<supports>THC Half-Fey Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You can communicate with beasts and plants as if you share a language. The starting attitude of beasts and plants is one step higher.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can communicate with beasts and plants as if you share a language. The starting attitude of beasts and plants is one step higher.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Faun" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_THE_FAUN">
		<supports>THC Half-Fey Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Whenever you make a long or high jump, you can roll a d8 and add the number to the number of feet you cover, even when making a standing jump. This extra distance costs movement as normal. Additionally, you have horns that you can use to make unarmed strikes. When you hit with them, you deal 1d6 + your Strength modifier Piercing damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your horns are natural weapons and deal 1d6+{{strength:modifier}} Piercing damage. Whenever you jump, roll 1d8 and add it to the number of feet you cover.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of Glamour" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_GLAMOUR">
		<supports>THC Half-Fey Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You know the <i>Disguise Self</i> spell, and can cast it without expending a spell slot. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell when you cast it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can cast Disguise Self at will, using {{mark of glamour:ability}} as your spellcasting ability.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Spellcasting Ability (Mark of Glamour)" supports="THC Half Fey Mark of Glamour Spellcasting Ability" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_GLAMOUR_INTELLIGENCE">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Glamour Spellcasting Ability</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your Mark of Glamour.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of glamour:ability" value="Intelligence" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Disguise Self (Mark of Glamour)" supports="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF|ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_GLAMOUR_WISDOM">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Glamour Spellcasting Ability</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your Mark of Glamour.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of glamour:ability" value="Wisdom" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Disguise Self (Mark of Glamour)" supports="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF|ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_GLAMOUR_CHARISMA">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Glamour Spellcasting Ability</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your Mark of Glamour.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of glamour:ability" value="Charisma" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Disguise Self (Mark of Glamour)" supports="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF|ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Naiad" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_THE_NAIAD">
		<supports>THC Half-Fey Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>If immersed in water, you can make yourself Invisible as a Bonus Action. You remain Invisible until you leave the water, end it with a Bonus Action, or die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>If immersed in water, you can make yourself Invisible. You remain Invisible until you leave the water, end it with a Bonus Action, or die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Pixie" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_THE_PIXIE">
		<supports>THC Half-Fey Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You have butterfly-like wings sprouting from your shoulder blades. You have a Fly Speed equal to your Speed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a {{speed}}ft. Fly Speed.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="speed" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of Seasons" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS">
		<supports>THC Half-Fey Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>ou become attuned to the primal magic of the seasons. Choose a season to associate yourself with: autumn, winter, spring, or summer. When finishing a Long Rest, you can change your season. As a bonus action, you can Fey Step, magically teleporting up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see and triggering an additional effect based on your current choice of season. If the effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma modifier (choose when you select this trait). You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
				<ul>
					<li><b><i>Autumn.</i></b> Immediately after you use your Fey Step, up to two creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</li>
					<li><b><i>Winter.</i></b> When you use your Fey Step, one creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you before you teleport must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</li>
					<li><b><i>Spring.</i></b> When you use your Fey Step, you can touch one willing creature within 5 feet of you. That creature then teleports instead of you, appearing in an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you.</li>
					<li><b><i>Summer.</i></b> Immediately after you use your Fey Step, each creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you takes Fire damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</li>
				</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your season of choice is {{mark of seasons:season}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Fey Step (Mark of Seasons)" supports="THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step" />
			<stat name="fey step:distance" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="8" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Autumn (Intelligence)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_AUTUMN_INTELLIGENCE">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Immediately after you use your Fey Step, up to two creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Immediately after you teleport, choose two creatures you can see within 10ft of you. They must succeed on a DC{{fey step:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Autumn" />
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Autumn (Wisdom)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_AUTUMN_WISDOM">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Immediately after you use your Fey Step, up to two creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Immediately after you teleport, choose two creatures you can see within 10ft of you. They must succeed on a DC{{fey step:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Autumn" />
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Autumn (Charisma)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_AUTUMN_CHARISMA">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Immediately after you use your Fey Step, up to two creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Immediately after you teleport, choose two creatures you can see within 10ft of you. They must succeed on a DC{{fey step:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to the creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Autumn" />
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Winter (Intelligence)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_WINTER_INTELLIGENCE">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Immediately after you use your Fey Step, one creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you before you teleport must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Immediately after you teleport, choose one creature you can see within 5ft of you. They must succeed on a DC{{fey step:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Winter" />
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Winter (Wisdom)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_WINTER_WISDOM">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Immediately after you use your Fey Step, one creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you before you teleport must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Immediately after you teleport, choose one creature you can see within 5ft of you. They must succeed on a DC{{fey step:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Winter" />
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Winter (Charisma)" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_WINTER_CHARISMA">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Immediately after you use your Fey Step, one creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you before you teleport must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Immediately after you teleport, choose one creature you can see within 5ft of you. They must succeed on a DC{{fey step:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or be Frightened until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Winter" />
			<stat name="fey step:dc" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spring" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_SPRING">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>When you use your Fey Step, you can touch one willing creature within 5 feet of you. That creature then teleports instead of you, appearing in an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Alternatively, you can touch one willing creature within 5ft of you, and they can teleport in your place.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Spring" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Summer" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS_SUMMER">
		<supports>THC Half Fey Mark of Seasons Fey Step</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Immediately after you use your Fey Step, each creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you takes Fire damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fey Step" action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/LR">
			<description>You can teleport up to {{fey step:distance}}ft to a space you can see. Choose any number of creatures you can see within 5ft. of you. They each take {{proficiency}} Fire damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of seasons:season" value="Summer" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Treetops" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_THE_TREETOPS">
		<supports>THC Half-Fey Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Your Speed increases by 10 feet, and you have a Climb Speed equal to your Speed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have a {{speed}}ft. Climb Speed.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed" value="10" />
			<stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fey Blessing: Fair Folk" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK">
		<requirements>[level:9],ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Level 9+, Half-Fey Feat</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Level 9+, Half-Fey Feat</em></p>
			<p>You are as beautiful and terrible as the dawn. You may choose a total of <b><u>TWO</u></b> traits selected from the Half Fey feat, or from the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Beanstalk.</i></b> You know the <i>Enlarge/Reduce</i> spell. You can cast it on yourself without expending a spell slot and without material components. When you do, the duration is Concentration until dispelled.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Fierce.</i></b> Creatures of your choice that start their turns within 20 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or be Charmed or Frightened (your choice) of you until the start of its next turn. If the creature’s saving throw is successful, it is immune to this ability for the next 24 hours.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Mind.</i></b> You can communicate telepathically to creatures within 60 feet of you. The contacted creature doesn't need to share a language with you to communicate in this way with it, but it must be able to understand at least one language.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Nimble.</i></b> When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Quick.</i></b> Your Speed increases by 20 feet.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of Resistance.</i></b> Choose two of the following damage types: Fire, Cold, Lightning, Poison, Psychic, Thunder, or Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage. You have Resistance to the chosen damage types. If you choose Poison, you have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Poisoned condition on yourself. If you choose Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage, choose cold iron or silver. Damage from magic weapons or weapons made of the chosen type bypass this resistance.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Stag.</i></b> Your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 damage of the same type, and your weapon attacks, including your unarmed strikes, are magical for the purpose of bypassing damage resistance. <i>Requires Mark of the Faun or a natural weapon trait, such as a Bite or Claw attack.</i></li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Unbound Realm.</i></b> The range of your Fey Step becomes 60 feet, and you regain all uses of Fey Step when you finish a Short or Long Rest. <i>Requires Fey Step.</i></li>
			</ul>
			</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are as beautiful and terrible as the dawn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Fair Folk" supports="THC Half-Fey Options||THC Fair Folk Options" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Beanstalk" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_THE_BEANSTALK">
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You know the <i>Enlarge/Reduce</i> spell. You can cast it on yourself without expending a spell slot and without material components. When you do, the duration is Concentration until dispelled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can cast Enlarge/Reduce on yourself at will. When you do, the duration is Concentration until dispelled.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enlarge Reduce spell (Mark of the Beanstalk)" supports="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE|ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Fierce" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_THE_FIERCE">
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Creatures of your choice that start their turns within 20 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or be Charmed or Frightened (your choice) of you until the start of its next turn. If the creature’s saving throw is successful, it is immune to this ability for the next 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Creatures of your choice that start their turns within 20ft. of you must make a DC{{mark of the fierce:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or be Charmed or Frightened (your choice) of you until the start of its next turn. If the creature’s saving throw is successful, it is immune to this ability for the next 24 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="mark of the fierce:dc" value="8" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="mark of the fierce:dc" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency"/>
			<stat name="mark of the fierce:dc" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Mind" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_THE_MIND">
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>You can communicate telepathically to creatures within 60 feet of you. The contacted creature doesn't need to share a language with you to communicate in this way with it, but it must be able to understand at least one language.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can communicate telepathically to creatures within 60 feet of you, as long as it understands one language.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Nimble" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_THE_NIMBLE">
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>When you’re subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw and only half damage if you fail. You can’t use this feature if you have the Incapacitated condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you are forced to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage and do not have the Incapacitated condition, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Quick" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_THE_QUICK">
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Your Speed increases by 20 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your Speed increases by 20 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed" value="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of Resistance" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_RESISTANCE">
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Choose two of the following damage types: Fire, Cold, Lightning, Poison, Psychic, Thunder, or Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage. You have Resistance to the chosen damage types. If you choose Poison, you have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Poisoned condition on yourself. If you choose Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage, choose cold iron or silver. Damage from weapons made of the chosen type bypass this resistance.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have Resistance to two damage types. Weapons made with {{mark of resistance:bypass}} bypass these resistances.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Mark of Resistance" supports="THC Fey Resistance||THC Mark of Resistance" number="2" />
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Resistance Bypass Material (Mark of Resistance)" supports="THC Mark of Resistance Bypass" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_RESISTANCE_BPS">
		<supports>THC Mark of Resistance</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have Resistance to Bludgeoning, Piercing, and Slashing damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_SLASHING" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cold Iron" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_RESISTANCE_BYPASS_COLD_IRON">
		<supports>THC Mark of Resistance Bypass</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Weapons made of Cold Iron bypass your Fey Resistances.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of resistance:bypass" value="Cold Iron" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_RESISTANCE_BYPASS_SILVER">
		<supports>THC Mark of Resistance Bypass</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Weapons made of Silver bypass your Fey Resistances.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat inline="true" name="mark of resistance:bypass" value="Silver" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Stag" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_THE_STAG">
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<prerequisites>Mark of the Faun or a natural weapon trait</prerequisites>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Mark of the Faun or a natural weapon trait</em></p>
			<p>Your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 damage of the same type, and your weapon attacks, including your unarmed strikes, are magical for the purpose of bypassing damage resistance.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d6 damage of the same type, and all of your unarmed and weapon attacks are magical for the purpose of bypassing Resistance.</description>
		</sheet>

	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Unbound Realm" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK_MARK_OF_THE_UNBOUND_REALM">
		<requirements>ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_HALF_FEY_MARK_OF_SEASONS||ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELADRIN_FEY_STEP</requirements>
		<supports>THC Fair Folk Options</supports>
		<prerequisites>Mark of Seasons or Fey Step</prerequisites>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Mark of Seasons or Fey Step</em></p>
			<p>The range of your Fey Step becomes 60 feet, and you regain all uses of Fey Step when you finish a Short or Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The range of your Fey Step becomes 60ft. and you regain all uses of Fey Step when you finish a Short or Long Rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="fey step:distance" value="60" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fey Blessing: Fey Courtier" type="Feat" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_COURTIER">
		<requirements>[level:12],ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FAIR_FOLK</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Level 12+, Fair Folk Feat</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Level 12+, Fey Courtier Feat</em></p>
			<p>You have become indistinguishable from trueborn fey by all but the keenest of folk. You may select a total of <b><u>TWO</u></b> traits selected from the Half Fey or Fair Folk feats, or from the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Forest Lord.</i></b> Beast and fey creatures you summon with spells are always friendly to you and your allies, and always obey your commands, and their weapon attacks count as magical for the purpose of bypassing damage resistance. Additionally, you ignore the material components of spells that summon beast and fey creatures, and your concentration on such spells can't be broken as a result of taking damage.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Grove Keeper.</i></b> Once on your turn, you can use 10 feet of your movement to step magically into one living tree within your reach and emerge from a second living tree within 60 feet of the first tree, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the second tree. Both trees must be Large or bigger.</li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of the Hunt.</i></b> When you take the Attack action and target a single creature with all of your attacks, you can choose a friendly creature you can see within 30 feet. That creature can use its Reaction to make one melee attack against a target of its choice. If you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you may attack an additional creature and still use this ability. <i>Requires Extra Attack.</i></li>
				<li><b><i>Mark of Immortality.</i></b> You no longer require food, drink, or sleep. You are Immune to the Blinded, Charmed, Deafened, Frightened, and Exhaustion conditions.</li>
			</ul>
			</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have become indistinguishable from trueborn fey by all but the keenest of folk.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Fey Courtier" supports="THC Half-Fey Options||THC Fair Folk Options||THC Fey Courtier Options" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Forest Lord" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_COURTIER_MARK_OF_THE_FOREST_LORD">
		<supports>THC Fey Courtier Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Beast and fey creatures you summon with spells are always friendly to you and your allies, and always obey your commands, and their weapon attacks count as magical for the purpose of bypassing damage resistance. Additionally, you ignore the material components of spells that summon beast and fey creatures, and your concentration on such spells can't be broken as a result of taking damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Beast and Fey creatures you summon with spells are always friendly to you and your allies, always obey your commands, and their weapon attacks count as magical for the purpose of bypassing damage resistance. Additionally, you ignore the material components of spells that summon Beast and Fey creatures, and your Concentration on such spells can't be broken as a result of taking damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Grove Keeper" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_COURTIER_MARK_OF_THE_GROVE_KEEPER">
		<supports>THC Fey Courtier Options</supports>
		<description>
				<p>Once on your turn, you can use 10 feet of your movement to step magically into one living tree within your reach and emerge from a second living tree within 60 feet of the first tree, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the second tree. Both trees must be Large or bigger.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description>You can use 10ft. of movement to magically step into a living tree within your reach and emerge from a second living tree within 60 feet of the first tree, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the second tree. Both trees must be Large or bigger.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of the Hunt" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_COURTIER_MARK_OF_THE_HUNT">
		<supports>THC Fey Courtier Options</supports>
		<prerequisites>Extra Attack</prerequisites>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Extra Attack feature.</em></p>
			<p>When you take the Attack action and target a single creature with all of your attacks, you can choose a friendly creature you can see within 30 feet. That creature can use its Reaction to make one melee attack against a target of its choice. If you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you may attack an additional creature and still use this ability. <i>Requires Extra Attack.</i></p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you take the Attack action and target a single creature with all of your attacks, you can choose a friendly creature you can see within 30ft. That creature can use its Reaction to make one melee attack against a target of its choice. If you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you may attack an additional creature and still use this ability.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mark of Immortality" type="Feat Feature" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_FEAT_FEY_BLESSING_FEY_COURTIER_MARK_OF_IMMORTALITY">
		<supports>THC Fey Courtier Options</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You no longer require food, drink, or sleep. You are Immune to the Blinded, Charmed, Deafened, Frightened, and Exhaustion conditions.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You no longer require food, drink, or sleep. You are Immune to the Blinded, Charmed, Deafened, Frightened, and Exhaustion conditions.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

<!-- Conditions -->
	<element name="Slowed" type="Information" source="Tregolani Homebrew Collection" id="ID_TREGOLANI_HB_INFORMATION_CONDITION_SLOWED">
	<description>
		<p>While you are Slowed, you experience the following effects:</p>
		<ul>
			<li><b><i>Limited Movement.</i></b> You must spend 1 extra foot of movement for every foot you move using your Speed.</li>
			<li><b><i>Attacks Affected.</i></b> Attack Rolls against you have Advantage.</li>
			<li><b><i>Saves Affected.</i></b> You have Disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.</li>
			<li><b><i>Limited Actions.</i></b> You can't take Reactions.</li>
		</ul>
	</description>
	</element>
</elements>
